Rishabh Agrawal

Software Developer | rishabh.agrawal@mavs.uta.edu | (817) 401-5713 | Arlington, Texas

SUMMARY

I am a software developer with experience in mobile and web platform who help companies reduce operation costs, make technical operations efficient, improve customer experience, and help expand business reach by developing the product to go mobile-first.

EDUCATION

M.S. in Computer Science, University of Texas At Arlington

May 2020

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, C, Spring boot, Python, JavaScript, SQL, MongoDB, XML, JSON, HTML Software Development: Scrum, Jira, Git, AWS, Jenkins, Docker, Eclipse, Android Studio Operating System: Mac OS, Linux, Microsoft Windows, Unix

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern, Copart Inc.

Aug 2019-Present, Dallas, Texas

- Designed and delivered a robust and scalable Java backend data service with microservices architecture to do CRUD operations for the Restful web service and persist data to the data layer with Spring JPA to the relational database
- Developed the new check printing API replacing check printing from old dot-matrix systems to the new MICR printers, saving the company >\$300K in annual check printing cost
- Configured and utilized Spring MVC annotation to manage URL mapping with controllers to send JSON requests for the communication between front-end and the middleware

Android Developer, TransLine Infra

Jan 2017 – Mar 2018, Noida, India

- Implemented application functionalities and optimizing the run-time performance
- Integrated databases, Firebase back-end, notification handling, user authentication, API integration in app
- Optimized the caching mechanism to reduce API calls and reduce power consumption by 20%
- Developed update patches and improvements for existing client projects

Site Engineer, TransLine Infra

Apr 2016– Jan 2017, Noida, India

- Performed website design, and development of concepts and deliverable milestones
- Successfully identified, diagnosed, and fixed website problems: broken links, inconsistency in design etc.
- Performed maintenance and updates on existing client Web projects
- Utilized HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Ajax, jQuery, and Bootstrap

PROJECTS

Robotics Project:

- Implemented path planning and motion control in a self-driving robot that can navigate around obstacles
- Implemented the mechanism to extinguish fire in a self-driving autonomous Lego robot
- Implemented autonomous stair climbing and descending mechanism in an autonomous Lego robot
- Programmed in C language using C4EV3 API for LEGO robots

Android Apps: (Side projects, using Android Studio and 3rd party libraries)

- Copy Save: stores copied text from the clipboard permanently, >2000 downloads with 3* ratings
- Text Scan+Translator: uses Vision API to recognize text from Camera in real-time, store text & translate
- Others: Tip Calculator, Math Quiz app, Fake Profile Generator, Brightness app, Wallpapers app

Hackathons Participated:

- HackUTA 2018: Developed Android app: MeeleMe that senses the highlighted character on Smash Bros
 player selection screen and speaks the key-combination for heavy attack of that player using Android SDK
- HackDFW 2018: Created web app on blockchain to create a decentralized web application for charities and their donations where the data is open to anyone but encrypted, using

Resume | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rishabh-agrawal94 | http://ssrishabh96.github.io